In our app if you hit the- button too many times
在我们的应用中 如果你多次点击这个按钮
we get a negative number of cups of coffee.
就会得到一个负数
That's a problem, because what does that even mean?
这是一个问题 负数有什么意义呢？
We probably shouldn't allow this to happen in our app.
我们不能让这样的情形发生在我们的应用中
And the earlier we deal with it within our app,
越早处理这个问题
then it will cause less headache for us later on.
后面的麻烦就越少
For example, we don't want to submit a bunch of orders to the coffee shop
例如 我们不想给咖啡店提供
with a negative number of cups of coffee.
负数杯咖啡的订单
And at the other end of the spectrum, there probably should also be a maximum
在数量范围的另一端 应该有一个
number of coffees that we allow the user to order in a single time.
限制用户单次购买的咖啡杯数的最大值
We can't really serve 10,000 cups of coffee at a time.
我们无法一次性提供10000杯咖啡
Now that we've identified the problem,
现在 我们已经发现问题了
let's decide on a better behavior for our app.
让我们把应用变得更好
How about if we only allow the customer to order between 1 and
如果我们限制用户一次可以定1
100 cups of coffee?
到100 杯咖啡 会怎么样呢？
In our app when the user tries to press the- button and it's already displaying
在我们的应用中 当用户点击 — 按钮的时候 它就会显示
1 cup of coffee, then the quantity shouldn't go below that.
1杯咖啡 然后数量不应该比1小了
Likewise, if there are 100 cups of coffee and
同样的 如果已经有100杯咖啡了
the user continues to press the + button, the quantity should stay at 100.
并且用户继续点击 + 按钮 数量将一直保持100
We can do this by something called input checking.
我们可以用被称为输入检查的方式达到这个效果
By checking what the user inputs into the app,
通过检查用户的输入
we can recognize bad input as soon as possible and
我们可以快速地识别错误的输入
then prevent the app from continuing the normal flow of execution.
阻止应用继续执行
For this quiz, make this change in your app.
这次测试中 对应用做如此改变
Assume that the app always starts at two cups of coffee when you first launch it.
假定应用首次启动时 就显示两杯咖啡
To find the right place to make the code change,
为了找到修改代码的正确地方
think about when the problem first occurs.
想一想问题第一次出现的时候
What button does the user press, and what code is triggered by that button?
用户点击了什么按钮 触发了什么代码？
Since the app has different behavior depending on whether the number of cups
因为应用在咖啡数量有效和无效时
of coffee is valid or
有不同的行为
not, think about using a control flow statement like an if else statement.
想一下使用控制流语句 比如 if else 语句
That way, the logic in the app can be different based on a certain condition.
这个方法中 应用中的逻辑可以根据不同的条件而不同
If the user is trying to order a number of cups of coffee outside of these
如果用户订购的咖啡数量超过这个
bounds, then figure out how to stop the app from continuing.
范围 那么就需要解决应用停止执行的这一问题
Once you make these changes, answer these questions.
一旦你修改完成 回答这些问题
Which method did you modify so
你修改了哪个方法
that the quantity does not go below 1 cup of coffee?
使得咖啡数量不会小于1
Write your answer in this box.
在这个框中写上你的答案
Then, which method did you modify so
然后 你修改了哪个方法
the quantity doesn't go above 100 cups of coffee?
使得咖啡数量不会超过100
Write your answer in this box.
在这个框中写上你的答案
As a hint, it may be useful for you to know that you can put a return statement
提示一下 你可以在
anywhere inside a method and that will cause you to exit the method early.
一个方法的任何部位加入 return 语句 这能够使你提早退出方法
Then the rest of the code after that will be skipped.
这样就会跳过方法中剩下的代码
Check the end chapter notes for more details.
查看结束章节 可以看到更多的细节
As a challenge,
作为一个挑战
you can extend the app to also add a toast message that explains to the user
你可以在应用中加入 Toast 消息 向用户解释
why the quantity isn't updating when it hits these bounds.
为什么当数量达到边界时 它就不会再更新了
This is what the toast message could look like in the app
在应用中 Toast 消息看起来应该是这个样子的
when you've hit the lower bound.
当数量达到下限时
If I hit the- button a bunch of times to try to go below 1 cup of coffee,
如果我多次点击 — 按钮 达到下限1时
it shows this toast message.
就会显示这个 Toast 消息
You cannot have less than 1 coffee.
你不能有小于 1 数量的咖啡
By the way, if you want to test that the upper bound works, instead of tapping
顺便说一句 如果你想要测试上限
the + button 99 times, you can just make a temporary change in the code.
不用点击 + 按钮99次 你可以暂时在代码中做一些修改
You can change the initial global quantity variable in the Java file and
即在 Java文件中修改初始的全局变量 quantity
the initial quantity value in the XML to start at a higher number
在 XML 文件中把 quantity 的初始值变大一些
like 99 instead of just 2.
比如用99 代替2
Then, you'll only have to hit the + button a couple of times to go over 100
然后你只需要点击两次 + 按钮
cups of coffee.
咖啡数量就会增加到100 了
I highly recommend testing this to make sure that your code works as expected
我强烈建议测试上限保证你的代码
for the upper bound.
遇到上限时能正常运行
When you're done with all of this, go ahead and continue.
如果完成了这些 继续下一节内容吧